Contact

mdsn85@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-saad-688874179 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

.NET Framework

JavaScript

Python (Programming Language)

Certifications

Data Analysis

DAT263x: Introduction to Artificial Intelligence (AI)

Introduction to Mobile Solution Development for the Enterprise

Mohammad Saad

FullStack (.Net core, Angular, Ionic, Sql Server)
United Arab Emirates

Summary

Experienced software engineer who loves Developing Software Solution for business and society. I have a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and Software Development. Skilled in analyze requirement, design business process, code business model and design easy functional user interface.

.

Experience

zero waste

FullStack (.Net core, Angular, Ionic, SqlServer)
March 2020 - Present (9 months)
Dubai. United Arab Emirates

Use Case: They hired me to develop Web and Mobile solution to enable people book appointment from available schedule to collect their recyclables. Users' request we be viewed by drivers to collect recycled.

System will reward user based on point granted to user on each collection.

Front End:

- I develop Hybrid mobile application using Ionic framework, Angular .
- Designs and develops User Interface for mobile applications using Ionic , JavaScript,and CSS.

Back End:

- Design database (Entity framework, Sql Server, Automapper)
- Develop API for data request Using .Net Core Web API
- Design architect and Deploy on Etisalat Cloud Services (iis Server)

Mrskips

FullStack (.Net core, Angular, Ionic, SqlServer)
June 2019 - February 2020 (9 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Use Case: They hired me to develop mobile application to connect Truck driver with Operation dept. and call center, to render all tasks instantly and

efficiently , then generate invoice after task completed , these invoices must be compatible with existing accounting software

Front End:

- I develop Hybrid mobile application using Ionic framework, Angular .
- Designs and develops User Interface for mobile applications using Ionic , JavaScript,and CSS.

Back End

- Design database (Entity framework, Sql Server)
- Develop API for data request Using .Net Core Web API
- Design architect and Deploy on Etisalat Cloud Services (iis Server)

Entrepreneur

Full Stack Engineer (.net , Javascript, Html, Css, SqlServer March 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Use Case: CRM software Manage customers' relationship from leads to invoice with one integrated software CRM.. http://www.skipscrm.com/

- Designs and develops User Interface for web applications using JavaScript, CSS, and HTML5.
- Design database and develop sql queries
- applies Net Web API's for mobile application
- Design and code high-quality web application using Microsoft, C#, and JavaScript library like(jquery, ajax, ...).
- Design and code high-quality hybrid mobile application using lonic platform , Angular and firebase.
- Design architect and manage of Etisalat Cloud Services
- Design and implement .NET Microservices: Architecture for Containerized .NET Applications

Saad Al hamadi Legal Office

Dotnet Developer (asp.net mvc, javascript, html, css)

April 2018 - December 2018 (9 months)

Dubai

Software for legal offiUse Case: Legal Assistant Software is developed to manage law firms and communicate with their clients easily and efficiently The legal assistant emulates the records of lawyers' offices and adds business intelligence.

- Designs and develops User Interface for web applications using JavaScript, CSS, and HTML5.
- Design database and develop sql queries
- Met with the company's clients; developed the design framework for the respective websites by collating information on the clients; business goals and objectives.
- Conducted comprehensive research covering the industry, target market, and financial costs for the purpose of creating a budget for the project.
- Presented clients with a series of mockups for the website.
- Performs regular audits to check on website data security, outdated applications and programs, and site functionality.

се

Prism

SAP Project Coordinator

May 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 8 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

project coordinator to be the liaison between the project manager of Client company and Prism

- Collect requirement from customer
- Configure master data to SAP backend
- Schedule and follow up consultation meeting

Mds

Dotnet Developer

May 2010 - April 2014 (4 years)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Design and Developing in house ERP for company using Visual Studio
 8. net
- Testing and quality control for new model implemented in ERP

syria tel

Dotnet Developer

January 2009 - February 2010 (1 year 2 months)

Syria

 Handled the task of developing new software to reward Syriatell customer (new form, design database)

Education

Tishreen University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2003 - 2018)